<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>golang on rm -rf /</title>
    <link>/categories/golang/</link>
    <description>Recent content in golang on rm -rf /</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 22:18:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/golang/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Reporting Vulnerabilities To Snyk</title>
      <link>/posts/snyk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 22:18:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/snyk/</guid>
      <description>Snyk is a CNA for Golang packages (and other popular languages). When I learned that they&amp;rsquo;d accept vulnerability reports, I decided to try them out with a couple of old bugs which I&amp;rsquo;d reported but got no response from the project author.
The turnaround on these issues was very quick (a couple of hours, on a weekend no less) and there are now two CVEs assigned: CVE-2020-7711 and CVE-2020-7731.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Golang: Panicking Safely</title>
      <link>/posts/panic/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 19:16:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/panic/</guid>
      <description>Golang code can panic, causing availability issues, maybe even a denial of service vector. Compared to C and C++, it&amp;rsquo;s pretty innocuous. Still, denial of service is a serious issue: why not just use recover in all goroutines and keep the show on the road?
An Example Consider the following code:
// buggy reads data from input 16 bytes at a time, munges it and then writes it to output func buggy(input, output string) error { in, err := os.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SO_REUASEADDR and Golang</title>
      <link>/posts/so_reuaseaddr-golang/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2017 13:53:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/so_reuaseaddr-golang/</guid>
      <description>A Flaky Test I was investigating a test which failed with a very low probability. It boiled down to this:
package main import ( &amp;#34;net&amp;#34; &amp;#34;time&amp;#34; ) func main() { //port zero means let the OS choose a free port 	l, err := net.Listen(&amp;#34;tcp&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;127.0.0.1:0&amp;#34;) if err != nil { panic(err) } addr := l.Addr().String() go func() { for { c, err := l.Accept() if err != nil { return } c.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leaking File Descriptors in Go</title>
      <link>/posts/file-descriptor-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2017 11:39:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/file-descriptor-go/</guid>
      <description>Golang, File Descriptors and Finalizers If you Open() a file in Golang and it goes out of scope, then it&amp;rsquo;ll be closed the next time the garbage collector runs as there&amp;rsquo;s a cleanup finalizer set when Open() is called.
You can see this in action in the following program:
package main import ( &amp;#34;fmt&amp;#34; &amp;#34;os&amp;#34; &amp;#34;runtime&amp;#34; ) func allocate() int { //use this file as our test subject 	_, sourceFile, _, ok := runtime.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2017-15042</title>
      <link>/posts/cve-2017-15042/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2017 14:46:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/cve-2017-15042/</guid>
      <description>I Went Looking For A STARTTLS Bug I&amp;rsquo;ve been putting together a cryptography course for my colleagues which focuses on mistakes. Its working title is Cryptography Done Wrong which should give you an idea of the tone. There&amp;rsquo;s a wealth of examples of systems assembled from sound cryptographic components which end up with security issues (for some definition of secure).
Over the years, TLS has been an excellent source of examples for such a course.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
