<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>security on rm -rf /</title>
    <link>/categories/security/</link>
    <description>Recent content in security on rm -rf /</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 13:32:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Luarocks MITM</title>
      <link>/posts/luarocks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 13:32:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/luarocks/</guid>
      <description>Background LuaRocks is a package manager for Lua. The executable &amp;ldquo;luarocks&amp;rdquo; allows users to
 download Lua packages and dependencies from luarocks.org (the default) upload packages to luarocks.org  Several months ago I found a man-in-the-middle vulnerability and reported it to the LuaRocks project via Gitter. I was directed to create a public issue on github. At the time of writing, there&amp;rsquo;s no CVE assigned by the project or github security notification.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reporting Vulnerabilities To Snyk</title>
      <link>/posts/snyk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 22:18:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/snyk/</guid>
      <description>Snyk is a CNA for Golang packages (and other popular languages). When I learned that they&amp;rsquo;d accept vulnerability reports, I decided to try them out with a couple of old bugs which I&amp;rsquo;d reported but got no response from the project author.
The turnaround on these issues was very quick (a couple of hours, on a weekend no less) and there are now two CVEs assigned: CVE-2020-7711 and CVE-2020-7731.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2017-15042</title>
      <link>/posts/cve-2017-15042/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2017 14:46:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/cve-2017-15042/</guid>
      <description>I Went Looking For A STARTTLS Bug I&amp;rsquo;ve been putting together a cryptography course for my colleagues which focuses on mistakes. Its working title is Cryptography Done Wrong which should give you an idea of the tone. There&amp;rsquo;s a wealth of examples of systems assembled from sound cryptographic components which end up with security issues (for some definition of secure).
Over the years, TLS has been an excellent source of examples for such a course.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
